ebayclassifieds.com 2019-06-25

# User Privacy Notice | eBay

We may disclose your personal information to the following parties for the following purposes:

### eBay Inc. corporate family members, who may use it to:

  * Provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions, and customer support)
  * Help detect, investigate, mitigate and prevent potentially fraudulent and illegal acts, violations of our User Agreement, and data security breaches
  * Provide you personalized advertising
  * Improve their products, sites, applications, services, tools, and marketing communications
  * Members of our eBay Inc. corporate family will use your personal information to send you marketing communications only if you have consented to receive such communications from them or if otherwise permitted by the law

### Service Providers and financial institutions partners as follows:

  * Third party service providers who help us to provide our Services, payment processing services, assist us in providing customize advertising, to assist us with the prevention, detection, mitigation, and investigation of potentially illegal acts, violations of our User Agreement, fraud and/or security breaches, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs, co-branded credit cards and other business operations
  * Third party financial institutions with whom we partner to offer financial products to you, for them to provide joint content and services (such as, registration, transactions and customer support). These third party financial institution partners will use your personal information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services
  * Third party shipping providers (e.g., DHL, UPS, USPS, etc.) with whom we share delivery address, contact information and shipment tracking information for the purposes of facilitating the delivery of items purchased and other delivery related communications
  * Third party providers of websites, applications, services and tools that we cooperate with so that they can publish or advertise your listings and their content on their websites or in their applications, services and tools. If we transfer personal information along with the content of your listings to third party providers, this will be solely on the basis of an agreement limiting use by the third party provider of such personal information to processing necessary to fulfil their contract with us and obligating the third party provider to take security measures with regard to such data. Third party providers are not permitted to sell, lease or in any other way transfer the personal information included in your listings to third parties

### Law enforcement, legal proceedings, and as authorized by law

  * To comply with our legal requirements, enforce our User Agreement, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property or safety
  * To law enforcement or governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request or legal process relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that exposes us, you, or any other of our users to legal liability. We will only disclose information we deem relevant to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state, postcode, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history
  * To participants of the eBay VeRO Program globally under confidentiality agreement, as we in our sole discretion deem necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, we will disclose seller’s name, street address, city, state, postcode, country, phone number, email address and company name to the participants of the eBay VeRO Program
  * To credit agencies or bureaus as authorized by applicable national laws (e.g. information on late or missed payments or other defaults on your account that may be reflected in your credit report or file)
  * To third parties involved in a legal proceeding, if they provide us with a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal basis, or we otherwise believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity

### Other eBay users as authorized by you or your use of our Services

  * When transacting with another user, the other user may request that we provide him/her with information about you necessary to complete the transaction, such as your name, account ID, email address, contact details, shipping and billing address, or other information from you needed to promote the reliability and security of the transaction
  * If a transaction fails, is put on hold, or is later invalidated, we may also provide the other user with details of the unsuccessful transaction
  * The other user receiving your information should only use it for purposes related to the transaction. Unless you have consented to receive marketing from them, they should not contact you for marketing purposes
  * Contacting users with unwanted or threatening messages is a violation of our User Agreement

### We may disclose your personal information to PayPal Inc. and its corporate family

  * To prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate potentially illegal acts, fraud and/or security breaches, and to assess and manage risk, including to alert you if fraudulent activities have been detected on your eBay or PayPal accounts
  * To provide customer services, including to help service your account or resolve disputes (e.g., billing or transactional disputes)
  * To facilitate the processing of payment cards when you pay within our Services with a payment card and we use PayPal to process your payment
  * To facilitate shipping and related services for purchases you made using PayPal

### Change of ownership

If we are subject to a merger or acquisition with/by another company, we may share information with them in accordance with our global privacy standards. Should such an event occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this privacy notice with respect to your personal information. If we intend to handle your personal information for any purposes not covered in this privacy notice, you will receive prior notification of the processing of your personal information for the new purposes.

We retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide the Services you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our policies.

### Learn more: How long we keep your personal information

Our specific retention times for personal information are documented in our regional records retention schedules. How long we retain personal information can vary significantly based on context of the Services we provide and on our legal obligations. The following factors typically influence retention periods:

  * **How long is the personal information needed to provide our Services?** This includes such things as maintaining and improving the performance of our products, keeping our systems secure, and maintaining appropriate business and financial records. This is the general rule that establishes the baseline for most of our data retention periods
  * **Is the personal information sensitive?** If so, a shortened retention time is generally appropriate
  * **Have you provided consent for a longer retention period?** If so, we will retain data in accordance with your consent
  * **Are we subject to a legal, contractual, or similar obligation to retain your personal information?** Examples can include mandatory data retention laws in the applicable jurisdiction, government orders to preserve data relevant to an investigation, or personal information retained for the purposes of litigation

After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we will dispose of it in a secure manner according to our data retention and deletion policies.

## Cookies & Similar Technologies

When you visit or interact with our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, we or our authorized service providers may use cookies and other similar technologies to help provide you with a better, faster, and safer experience, and for advertising and marketing purposes. You can read our full User Cookie Notice for more information.

## How do we protect your personal information

We protect your personal information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls. For more information about staying safe while buying and selling online, or to report an issue with your account please visit our [Security Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://pages.ebay.com/securitycenter/index.html).

## Global Privacy Standards

We have established a set of global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as our Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations within our eBay Inc. corporate family. More information about our BCRs and our global privacy standards is available at our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/).

## Data Controllers and Data Protection Officers

Learn more about who is your data controller, and is responsible for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards, this privacy notice, as well as any applicable national laws.

### Learn more: Data Controllers and Data Protection Officers

If you reside in the United States, you are contracting with eBay Inc., 2025 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA and, if you use our payments services, also with eBay Commerce Inc., 2025 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA, for such payments services.

If you reside outside of the United States, you are contracting with one of our international eBay companies, as follows:

  * If you reside in Canada you are contracting with eBay Canada Limited, 500 King Street West, Suite 200, Toronto, ON M5V 1L9, Canada;
  * If you reside in a country within the European Union (except the United Kingdom) you are contracting with eBay GmbH, Albert-Einstein-Ring 2-6, 14532 Kleinmachnow, Germany;
  * If you reside in the United Kingdom you are contracting with eBay (UK) Limited, 1 More London Place, London, SE1 2AF, United Kingdom;
  * If you reside in India you are contracting with eBay Singapore Services Pte Ltd, 10 Collyer Quay, #10-01 Ocean Financial Centre, Singapore 049315;
  * If you reside in any other country, you are contracting with eBay Marketplaces GmbH, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005 Bern, Switzerland
  * If you use our eBay Customer Guarantee services and reside in France, Italy or Spain, you are also contracting with eBay Services S.à r.l, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg for such specific services

The company you are contracting with is your data controller, and is responsible for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards, this privacy notice, as well as any applicable national laws.

Your data controller may transfer data to other members of the eBay Inc. corporate family who have signed our BCRs, as described in this privacy notice.

We may process and retain your personal information on our servers in the U.S. and elsewhere in the world where our data centers are located.

Where we have a legal obligation to do so, we have appointed data protection officers (DPOs) to be responsible for the privacy program at each of the respective data controllers. You can contact any of our DPOs via the Contact Us information detailed below in this privacy notice.

## Other important privacy information

This section describes some additional privacy information related to your use of our Services that you may find important.

### Learn more: Other important privacy information

### When you share your personal information on our sites or applications – what happens?

Other users have access to the information you share on eBay. For example, other users can see your bids, purchases, items for sale, your collections, the sellers and collections you follow, storefronts, feedback, ratings, product reviews and associated comments. Other users can also see any information you chose to share in your profile or your collections.

When you use our Services, your public user ID may be displayed and available to the public and associated with all of your public eBay activity. Notices sent to other users about suspicious activity and notice violations on our sites may refer to your public user ID and specific items. If you associate your name with your user ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name may then be able to identify your eBay activities.

To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, shipping and financial information as necessary to facilitate your transactions and collect payments. However, when users are involved in a transaction, they have access to each other's name, user ID, email address and other contact and shipping information.

### Your responsibilities over transactional information you receive through eBay

When you transact with another user, we enable you to obtain or we may provide you with the personal information of the other user (such as their name, account ID, email address, contact details, shipping and billing address) to complete the transaction. Independent from us, you are the controller of such data and we encourage you to inform the other user about your privacy practices and respect their privacy. In all cases, you must comply with the applicable privacy laws, and must give the other user a chance to remove them from your database and them a chance to review what information you have collected about them.

You may use the personal information that you have access to only for eBay transaction-related purposes, or for other services offered through eBay (such as escrow, shipping, fraud complaints, and member-to-member communications), and for purposes expressly consented by the user to whom the information relates. Using personal information of other users that you have access to for any other purpose constitutes a violation of our User Agreement.

### Unwanted or threatening email

We do not tolerate abuse of our Services. You do not have permission to add other users to your mailing list (email or postal), call, or send him/her text messages for commercial purposes, even if this user purchased something from you, unless the user has given his/her explicit consent. Sending unwanted or threatening email and text messages is against our User Agreement. To report eBay-related spam or spoof emails please forward the email to [spam@ebay.com](mailto:spam@ebay.com) or [spoof@ebay.com](mailto:spoof@ebay.com).

### Communication tools

We may scan messages automatically and check for spam, viruses, phishing and other malicious activity, illegal or prohibited content or violations of our User Agreement, this privacy notice or our other policies.

### Children's Privacy

Our websites are general audience websites and not intended for children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from users deemed to be children under their respective national laws.

### Third Party Privacy Practices

This privacy notice addresses only our use and handling of personal information we collect from you in connection with providing you our Services. If you disclose your information to a third party, or visit a third party website via a link from our Services, their privacy notices and practices will apply to any personal information you provide to them or they collect from you.

We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your personal information once you provide it to a third party and we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your personal information. This is true even where the third parties to whom you disclose personal information are bidders, buyers or sellers on our site.

## Contact Us

If you have a question or a complaint about this privacy notice, our global privacy standards, or our information handling practices, you can reach the Global Privacy Office in writing at: eBay Inc, Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Office, 2065 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, USA.

You can find more information on how to contact us and our data protection officers at our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/).

Your right to file complaints with a data protection supervisory authority remains unaffected.

## Previous privacy policy

### Previous privacy policy (revised on 1 May 2015 and effective for existing users until 31 May 2018)

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [ https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request \- opens in new window or tab](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

## Scope and Consent

This Privacy Notice describes our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information. It applies to any eBay site where this Privacy Notice appears in the footer, and to any eBay application, service, or tool (collectively "Services") where this Privacy Notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices. **By using our Services and/or registering for an account with us, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Notice and our User Agreement , and you are consenting to our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information as described in this Privacy Notice.**

### Learn more: Scope and Consent

This Privacy Notice describes our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information. It applies to any eBay site where this Privacy Notice appears in the footer, and to any eBay application, service, or tool (collectively "Services") where this Privacy Notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices.

**By using our Services and/or registering for an account with us, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Notice and our User Agreement, and you are consenting to our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information as described in this Privacy Notice.** If you do not provide the information we require, we may not be able to provide all of our Services to you.

If you reside in the United States, you are contracting with eBay Inc., 2065 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA. If you reside outside of the United States, you are contracting with one of our international eBay companies:

  * If you reside in a country within the European Union you are contracting with eBay Europe S.à.r.l., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg
  * If you reside in India, you are contracting with eBay India Private Limited, 14th Floor, North Block, R-Tech Park, Western Express Highway, Goregaon (East), Mumbai 400063, Maharashtra, India
  * Starting on July 1, 2017, you are contracting with eBay Canada Limited, 500 King Street West, Suite 200, Toronto, ON M5V 1L9, Canada, if you reside in Canada
  * Starting on August 1, 2017, you are contracting with eBay (UK) Limited, 5 New Street Square, London, EC4A 3TW, United Kingdom, if you reside in the United Kingdom
  * If you reside in any other country, you are contracting with eBay International AG, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005 Bern, Switzerland

The company you are contracting with is your data controller, and is responsible for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards as well as any applicable national laws. Your data controller may transfer data to other members of the eBay Inc. corporate family as described in this Privacy Notice. We may process and retain your personal information on our servers in the U.S. and elsewhere in the world where our data centers are located.

### Personal Information

"Personal information" is information that can be associated with a specific person and could be used to identify that specific person whether from that data or from that data and other information that eBay Inc. has or is likely to have access to. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it can no longer be used to identify a specific person, whether in combination with other information or otherwise.

### Changes to this Notice

We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time by posting the amended terms on this site. All amended terms automatically take effect 30 days after they are posted. We will announce any material changes to this Privacy Notice through the eBay Message Center and/or via email.

## Global Privacy Standards

eBay Inc. has established global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed or retained within our eBay Inc. corporate family.

### Learn more: Global Privacy Standards

eBay Inc. has established global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as our Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed, or retained within our eBay Inc. corporate family. Our BCRs have been approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators. That means we are treating your personal information everywhere within our eBay Inc. corporate family according to European Union privacy standards. More information about our BCRs and our global privacy standards is available at our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/privacy).

## Collection

We collect, process, and retain personal information from you and any devices (including mobile devices) you may use when you: use our Services, register for an account with us, provide us information on a web form, update or add information to your account, participate in community discussions, chats, or dispute resolution, or when you otherwise correspond with us regarding our Services.

### Learn more: Collection

We collect, process, and retain personal information from you and any devices (including mobile devices) you may use when you: use our Services, register for an account with us, provide us information on a web form, update or add information to your account, participate in community discussions, chats, or dispute resolution, or when you otherwise correspond with us regarding our Services.

The personal information we collect includes the following:

**Personal information you give us when you use our Services or register for an account with us**

  * Identifying information such as your name, addresses, telephone numbers or email addresses when you register for an account with us
  * Bidding, buying, or selling information you provide during a transaction, or other transaction-based content that you generate or that is connected to your account as a result of a transaction you are involved in
  * Other content that you generate, or that is connected to your account (such as adding items to your basket, adding items to your Watch List, creating collections, and following other collections and sellers)
  * Financial information (such as credit card or bank account numbers) in connection with a transaction
  * Postage, billing and other information used to purchase or post an item, as well as, where postal services are provided through one of our programs, information required to clear customs (such as Tax ID or other identification numbers) and relevant postage information (such as tracking numbers and tracking updates)
  * In some instances, when you use our Services, you may provide age, gender, interests and favorites
  * You may also provide us other information through a web form, by updating or adding information to your account, through your participation in community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, or when you otherwise correspond with us regarding our Services
  * Additional information we are required or authorized by applicable national laws to collect and process in order to authenticate or identify you or to verify the information we have collected

### **Personal information we collect automatically when you use our Services or register for an account with us**

  * We also collect information about your interaction with our Services, your advertising preferences, and your communications with us. This is information we receive from the devices (including mobile devices) you use when you use our Services, register for an account with us, provide us information on a web form, update or add information to your account, participate in community discussions, chats, or dispute resolution, or when you otherwise correspond with us regarding our Services. This information comprises the following: Device ID or unique identifier, device type, ID for advertising, and unique device token
  * Geo-location information, including location information from your mobile device. Keep in mind that most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services by any application on your mobile device in the device's settings' menu
  * Computer and connection information such as statistics on your page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, your IP address, your browsing history, and your web log information

### Personal information we collect using cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers, and similar technologies to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take on our Services, within our advertising or e-mail content. For more information about our use of these technologies and how to control them, see our notice on Cookies, web beacons and similar technologies.

**Personal information from other sources**

  * We may supplement the personal information we collect with information from third parties and add it to your account information. For example, we may collect and use demographic information that is publically available, additional contact information, credit check information, and information from credit bureaus, as allowed by applicable national laws
  * We may allow you to share information with social media sites, or use social media sites to create your account or to connect your account with the respective social media site. Those social media sites may give us automatically access to certain personal information retained by them about you (e.g., content viewed by you, content liked by you, and information about the advertisements you have been shown or may have clicked on, etc.). If you provide us with access to any site with video content, then you agree that we may share your video viewing with, or obtain information about your video viewing from, third-party social media sites for at least two years or until you withdraw consent. You control the personal information you allow us to have access to through the privacy settings on the applicable social media site and the permissions you give us when you grant us access to your personal information retained by the respective social media site about you. By associating an account managed by a social media site with your account and authorizing us to have access to this information, you agree that we may collect, use and retain the information provided by these social media sites in accordance with this Privacy Notice
  * If you give us personal information about someone else, you must do so only with their explicit and prior consent. You have to inform them how we collect, use, disclose, and retain their personal information according to our Privacy Notice.

## Use and Retention

We use the personal information we collect to: provide and improve our Services, provide you with a personalized experience on our sites (especially, by offering you services and items that you may like), contact you about your account and our Services, provide you customer service, provide you with personalized advertising and marketing, and detect, prevent, mitigate, and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities.

We retain your personal information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we may retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with national laws, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our User Agreement and take other actions permitted or required by applicable national laws.

### Learn more: Use and Retention

We use the personal information we collect to: provide and improve our Services, to provide you with a personalized experience on our sites (especially, by offering you services and items that you may like), to contact you about your account and our Services, to provide you customer service, to provide you with personalized advertising and marketing, and to detect, prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities. We may use and retain your personal information as follows:

### Provide, improve, and personalize our Services

  * Provide access to and use of our Services
  * Offer you site content that includes items and services that you may like
  * Keep track of your basket, your Watch List, your collections, and collections and sellers that you have chosen to follow
  * Give you access to your purchase history, scores, bids, internal messages and other feature
  * Provide you with credit offers and opportunities on behalf of other members of our eBay Inc. corporate family and their financial institution partners, keeping in mind we do not share any financial information with them without your explicit consent
  * Customize, measure, and improve our Services
  * Provide other services requested by you as described when we collect the information
  * We may use geo-location information to provide you with location based services (such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content)

### Contact you about your account and provide you customer service

  * Contact you to notify you regarding your account, to troubleshoot problems with your account, to resolve a dispute, to collect fees or monies owed, to poll your opinions through surveys or questionnaires, or as otherwise necessary to provide you customer service
  * Contact you as necessary to enforce our User Agreement, applicable national laws, and any agreement we may have with you
  * For these purposes we may contact you via email, telephone, text messages, and postal mail. When contacting you via telephone, to ensure efficiency, we may use autodialed or pre-recorded calls and text messages as described in our User Agreement. Message and data rates may apply

### Personalize our advertising and marketing communications

  * Personalize, measure, and improve our advertising based on your advertising customization preferences
  * Contact you, either via email, telephone, text messages, and postal mail in order to: offer you coupons, discounts and special promotions, and inform you about our Services and those of our eBay Inc. corporate family. We will use the contact information you have provided to contact you by e-mail, SMS text and/or telephone if you have consented to such contact. Message and data rates may apply
  * Deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences

### Prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities

  * Prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraud, security breaches, potentially prohibited or illegal activities
  * Enforce our Privacy Notice, our User Agreement or other policies

We retain your personal information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we may retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with national laws, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our User Agreement and take other actions permitted or required by applicable national laws. After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we dispose of it in a secure manner according to our data retention and deletion policies.

## Choice

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you, send you marketing information, and provide you with personalized advertising, and whether you want to stay signed into your account.

### Learn more: Choice

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you, to send you marketing information, how we provide you with customized and relevant advertising, and whether you want to stay signed into your account.

### Communication preferences

You can control the methods by which we may contact you about your account, and your buying and selling activities in the Communication Preference section within your My eBay. There, you can also control your member-to-member communications preferences setting and choose which newsletters and promotions you want to receive.

### Marketing

If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can unsubscribe from the link in the email you received, change your Communication Preferences within My eBay, or indicate your communication preferences within the direct communication from us. Keep in mind, we do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

### Advertising

If you do not wish to participate in our advertising personalization programs, you can opt-out by following the directions provided within the applicable advertisement, or directly at our AdChoice program. The effect of an opt-out will be to stop personalized advertising, but it will still allow the collection of information for certain purposes such as usage, research, analytics and internal online services operation purposes). In addition to that, we do not allow third parties to track or collect your personal information on our sites for their own advertising purposes without your explicit consent.

### Signed in

When you sign in to your account on our Services, we may give you the option to stay signed in to your account for a certain period of time. If you are using a public or shared computer, we encourage you not to choose to stay signed in. You or any other user of the computer/browser you signed in on will be able to view and access most parts of your account and take certain specific actions during this signed in period without any further authorization. The specific actions and account activities that you or any other user of this computer/browser may take include:

  * Bid, buy or make an offer on an item
  * Check out or add items to your cart
  * Purchase an item with PayPal using Faster Checkout (if enabled in your account)
  * View the activity header
  * View the My eBay page
  * View or edit the Watch List
  * View order details
  * Leave Feedback
  * View the profile page
  * Send member-to-member messages
  * Conduct after-sale activities, like leaving Feedback, canceling orders, requesting returns or submitting claims

If you attempt to change your password, username, update any other account information or attempt other account activity beyond those listed above, you will be asked to enter your password.

You can typically end your signed in session by either signing out and/or clearing your cookies. If you have certain browser privacy settings enabled, simply closing your browser may also end your signed in session. If you are using a public or shared computer you should sign out and/or clear your cookies when you are done using our Services in order to protect your account and your personal information.

### Withdraw consent

If you withdraw your consent for the use or disclosure of your personal information for purposes set out in this Privacy Notice you may not have access to all our Services and we might not be able to provide you all of the Services and customer support offered to our users and authorized under this Privacy Notice and our User Agreement.

## Access

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and that you have the ability to access it and make corrections to it.

### Learn more: Access

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and that you have the ability to access and make corrections to it. This includes the following:

  * You can see, review and change your personal information by signing in to your account. Please update your personal information immediately if it changes or is inaccurate
  * Once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable national laws
  * We will honor any statutory right you might have to access, modify or erase your personal information. To request access and to find out whether any fees may apply, if permitted by applicable national laws, please contact us following the instructions in the Contact Us section below. Where you have a statutory right to request access or request the modification or erasure of your personal information, we can still withhold that access or decline to modify or erase your personal information in some cases in accordance with applicable national laws, but will give you reasons if we do so

## Disclosure

We may disclose your personal information to other members of the eBay Inc. corporate family or to third parties. This disclosure may be required for us to provide and to provide you access to our Services, to comply with our legal obligations, to enforce our User Agreement, to facilitate our marketing and advertising activities, or to prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities related to our Services. We do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing and advertising purposes without your explicit consent.

### Learn more: Disclosure

We may disclose your personal information to other members of the eBay Inc. corporate family or to third parties. This disclosure may be required for us to provide and to provide you access to our Services, to comply with our legal obligations, to enforce our User Agreement, to facilitate our marketing and advertising activities, or to prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities related to our Services. We minimize the amount of personal information we disclose to what is directly relevant and necessary to accomplish the specified purpose. As stated above, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing and advertising purposes without your explicit consent.

We may disclose your personal information to the following parties and for the following purposes:

### [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us/corporate-family), who may use it to:

  * provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions, and customer support)
  * help detect and prevent potentially fraudulent and illegal acts, violations of our User Agreement, and data security breaches
  * provide you personalized advertising
  * guide decisions about their products, sites, applications, services, tools, and marketing communications. Members of our eBay Inc. corporate family will use your personal information to send you marketing communications only if you have consented to receive such communications from them

### Service Providers and financial institutions partners

  * Third party service providers who help us to provide our Services, payment processing services, assist us in providing customize advertising, to assist us with the prevention, detection, mitigation, and investigation of potentially illegal acts, violations of our User Agreement, fraud and/or security breaches, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs, co-branded credit cards and other business operations
  * Third party financial institution partners who may offer financial products to you, for them to provide joint content and services (such as, registration, transactions and customer support). These third party financial institution partners will use your personal information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services

### **Law enforcement, legal proceedings, and as authorized by law**

  * to comply with our legal requirements, enforce our User Agreement, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property or safety
  * to law enforcement or governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other of our users to legal liability. We will only disclose information we deem relevant to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state, postcode, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history
  * to participants of the eBay VeRO Program globally under confidentiality agreement, as we in our sole discretion deem necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, we will disclose seller's name, street address, city, state, postcode, country, phone number, email address and company name to the participants of the eBay VeRO Program
  * to credit agencies or bureaus as authorized by applicable national laws (e.g. information on late or missed payments or other defaults on your account that may be reflected in your credit report or file)
  * to third parties involved in a legal proceeding, if they provide us with a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, or we otherwise believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity

### Other eBay users as authorized by you or your use of our Services

When transacting with another user, the other user may request and we may provide him/her with information about you necessary to complete the transaction, such as your name, account ID, email address, contact details, shipping and billing address, or other information from you needed to promote the reliability and security of the transaction. If a transaction is held, fails, or is later invalidated, we may also provide the other user with details of the unsuccessful transaction. The other user receiving your information is not allowed to use this information for purposes unrelated to the transaction, such as to contact you for marketing purposes, unless you have express consented to it. Contacting users with unwanted or threatening messages is a violation of our User Agreement.

### Data disclosure to PayPal Inc. and its corporate family

We may disclose your personal information to PayPal Inc. and its corporate family for the following purposes:

  * to prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate potentially illegal acts, fraud and/or security breaches, and to assess and manage risk, including to alert you if fraudulent activities have been detected on your eBay or PayPal accounts
  * to provide customer services, including to help service your account or resolve disputes (e.g., billing or transactional disputes)
  * to facilitate the processing of payment cards when you pay within our Services with a payment card and we use PayPal to process your payment
  * to facilitate shipping and related services for purchases you made using PayPal

### Change of Ownership

If we were to merge with or be acquired by another company, we may share information with them in accordance with our global privacy standards. Should such an event occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Notice with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be collected, used, disclosed, or retained for any purposes not covered in this Privacy Notice, you will receive prior notification of the processing of your personal information for the new purposes.

## Security

We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls.

### Learn more: Security

We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls. If you believe your account has been abused, please contact us following the instructions in the Contact Us section below.

## Important Information

This section describes some additional important information related to your use of our Services.

### Learn more: Important Information

This section describes some additional important information related to your use of our Services. There are just a few more pieces of important privacy information related to your use of our Services that we need to cover:

### When you share your personal information on our sites or applications - what happens?

Other users have access to the information you share on eBay. For example, other users can see your bids, purchases, items for sale, your collections, the sellers and collections you follow, storefronts, Feedback, ratings and associated comments. Other users can also see any information you chose to share in your profile or your collections.

Your username is displayed throughout eBay and is available to the public. It is connected to all of your eBay activity. Notices sent to other users about suspicious activity and notice violations on our sites refer to User IDs and specific items. So if you associate your name with your User ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name will be able to personally identify your eBay activities.

To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, shipping and financial information as necessary to facilitate your transactions and collect payments. However, when users are involved in a transaction, they have access to each other's name, User ID, email address and other contact and shipping information.

### How you should use the information you receive on eBay

When you are in a transaction with another user, we enable you to obtain or we may provide you with the personal information of the other user (such as his/her name, account ID, email address, contact details, shipping and billing address) to complete the transaction. We encourage you to inform the other user about your privacy practices and respect his/her privacy. In all cases, you must give the other user a chance to remove himself/herself from your database and give him/her a chance to review what information you have collected about them.

You may use the personal information that you have access to only for eBay transaction-related purposes, or for other services offered through eBay (such as escrow, shipping, fraud complaints, and member-to-member communications), and for purposes expressly consented by the user to whom the information relates. Using personal information of other users that you have access to for any other purpose constitutes a violation of our User Agreement.

### Unwanted or threatening email

We do not tolerate abuse of our Services. You do not have permission to add other users to your mailing list (email or postal), call, or send him/her text messages for commercial purposes, even if this user purchased something from you, unless the user has given his/her explicit consent. Sending unwanted or threatening email and text messages is against our User Agreement. To report eBay-related spam or spoof emails please forward the email to [spam@ebay.com](mailto:spam@ebay.com) or [spoof@ebay.com](mailto:spoof@ebay.com).

### Children's Privacy

Our websites are general audience websites, and our Services are not intended for children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from users in this age group.

### Third Party Privacy Practices

This Privacy Notice addresses only the use and disclosure of personal information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, or if you are directed to a third party website, their privacy notices and practices will apply.

We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your information once you provide it to a third party and we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your information. This is true even where the third parties to whom you disclose personal information are bidders, buyers or sellers on our sites.

## Questions or Complaints

If you have a question or a complaint about this Privacy Notice, our global privacy standards, or our information handling practices, you can reach our Global Privacy Office in writing by sending us a letter or postcard to: eBay Inc, Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Office, 2065 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, USA or follow the instructions on how to contact us posted at our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us).

### Learn more: Questions or Complaints

If you have a question or a complaint about this Privacy Notice, our global privacy standards, or our information handling practices, you can reach the Global Privacy Office in writing by sending us a letter or postcard to: eBay Inc, Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Office, 2065 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, USA.

You can also find more information on how to contact us at our [eBay Privacy Center](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us).
